Hello.
So here we will be talking about operating principle.
So how NFC works.
How near-field communication technology works.
Near-field communication is a wireless communication technology that allows devices to communicate with
each other over short distances, typically less than four centimeters.
Unlike other wireless communication technologies such as Bluetooth and Wi-Fi, NFC does not require
pairing or network setup.
NFC works by using electromagnetic radio fields to establish a connection between two devices.
One device acts as an initiator and generates an RF field that can power the passive target device.
When I say initiator, I mean reader.
A PCD and when I say target device, I mean a card or PC.
So the initiator then modulates the field to send data to the target device.
This process is known as inductive coupling.
And this is what makes NFC unique from other wireless communication technology.
So how is the operating principle in high frequency mode?
This is a quick view regarding the communication between a reader and a card, or between a polling
device and a listening device, or also between a PC and a PC.
In high frequency that characterize the contactless field or the near field communication NFC.
We will get back to this later in detail.
But to give you a first idea, the contactless smart card or as mentioned in the picture, a listening
device is a smart card that uses inductive coupling to communicate with its coupler or polling device.
Inductive coupling is the principle behind electronic or electric transformers.
A primary coil.
A primary coil is powered by an AC voltage and creates a magnetic field.
This magnetic field induces a current in the secondary coil.
In the case of contactless cards, the primary coil is driven by a sinusoidal voltage.
At 1350 56MHz, as I said before, the frequency of 1350 six megahertz is the one that characterizes
the NFC technology and hence creates a magnetic field with a 1350 six megahertz carrier frequency.
So high frequency radio band.
This magnetic field is not constrained in a confined volume, as it would be the case in an actual transformer.
Instead, the fields floats virtually freely within a part of the open air, limited only by the directivity
of the coil and the decrease of the magnetic waves.
This coil and its driving circuit, forming the primary of a virtual transformer, is named the proximity
coupling device, so the PCD the reader.
When a mobile secondary coil, which is the mobile, which is the secondary coil, is moved into the
part of the space where the PCD field floods the transformer, once virtual now becomes real, the flow
of the magnetic field through the secondary coil provides electrical power to a secondary passive circuit.
As you may have guessed, this mobile part of the transformer made of a coil and of an electronic circuit
or a chip, which is the proximity integrated circuit card pick.
So how is the physical operation in high frequency?
In this part I'm going to present the physical operation in high frequency or the physical operation
let's say of the NFC technology.
So first for any communication we need two devices a PCD reader or a pick a card, the PCD, which is
our reader and the pick which is our card.
Please remember that the card answers only when it's exposed in the field generated by the reader.
And if the reader sends a comment.
So this means that the card is useful.
Uh, sorry is useless when it's not in the sight.
I mean, in the field generated by the reader.
Okay.
So for example, when you are in a restaurant, you need to put your card in the field generated by
the reader that the waiter will use in order to be able to do transaction in order to be able to pay.
So the PC or the controller or the microcontroller will send some data to the reader, which are in
a byte format.
So the first when we send the data from the PC to the encoder to the reader, they will be in a byte
format.
This encoder, which is included in the reader, will convert it to a bit format.
Then the modulator of the reader will convert this bits here, and then we will have a waveform signal
as an output.
So our output here will be.
A waveform like this for example.
In fact, the field generated by the reader is in fact a perfect sinusoidal.
It's a perfect sinusoidal signal.
Okay, that's how it looks.
A field generated by the by the reader.
Okay.
This waveform or this field, which is, as I said, a sinusoidal signal will be delivered through the
readers antenna.
So in fact it will be generated.
It will be given to the card through the antenna of the reader.
And once the card is in the field, it will activate the card through the interaction with the card's
antenna.
What does it mean?
In fact, it means that, as I said, the card basically is useless and the activation of the card like
we are, we will be able to wake up the car to make it functional.
When we put it inside the this field, which is given by the antenna of the reader.
So this alternating magnetic field around the reader readers antenna will induce a current in the cards
antenna.
This is how it works.
So this current is used to power the card and allow I mean allow the car to communicate with the reader.
These two devices here are designed to exchange data in both directions.
A comment from the reader, then an answer from the card, then a comment from the reader, then an
answer from the card.
However, by the way, this part of communication, I mean digital communication between the reader
and the card.
When I say comment, answer, comment, answer will be detailed in one of the following presentations.
We will go back to this part in detail to present the bytes the the the the name of comments or answer.
What's the purpose of them?
What's the information that we can extract from them, and so on and so on.
So let's get back to this part.
These two devices are designed to exchange data in both directions.
As I said by the way.
All of this communication, as I said I would like to remember to to repeat it every time is based in,
in an exchange of information and also and also antenna communication, the antenna of the reader communicate
with the antenna of the card.
So regarding the Pic regarding the card, in fact, it contains a microchip that stores information
and an antenna that transmits data to the reader when in close proximity.
This answer, or let's say this data, will be presented by a transformation of the waveform sent by
the reader.
I will detail this later in the analog presentation in the analog aspects.
So.
As I said, this data will be presented by a transformation of the waveform sent by the reader that
will pass through the demodulator of the reader.
Then the output will be in bit format, and in the end, we will get the answer of the card in byte
format from the decoder of the reader.
So it will be in fact the same thing.
Here we will have a waveform.
Here you will have bits format, and here we will have byte by byte format as an output.
So this whole operation is presented by the layers one and two, ISO 14,140 3-1 and ISO 14,440 3-2 standards
that I am going to present through the the fourth section.
So here in the last slide I was talking about the standards many times.
So in fact the RFID, the radio frequency identification, high frequency standards are three.
So we have three standards details that details the NFC communication between a card and a read between
a PC and the PCD.
So first of all, ISO 14,443, which is an international standard that defines proximity cards that
used for identification cards may be type A and type B.
Both of them communicate via radio at 1350 six megahertz, which is, as I said, the frequency that
characterizes the RFID high frequency.
The main differences between these types concern modulation methods, coding schemes, and protocol
initialization procedures.
Both type A and type B cards use the same transmission protocol.
ISO 14,443 systems operate at a distance less than ten centimeters.
As I said, we will get back to the type A and type B communications in detail, and we will also get
back to the one of the main questions of the NFC technology, which is what's the difference, exact
difference between type A and type B, why the chip manufacturer can choose to fabricate a card or a
chip of type A or a type B.
So all of the details about the ISO 14,143 standard will be presented through the fifth and the sixth
sections.
Then we have ISO 15 693 standard, which is an ISO standard for vicinity cards.
Cards which can be read from a greater distance as compared with proximity cards.
ISO 15,693 systems operate also at 1350 six megahertz frequency, and offer maximum read distance of
1 to 1.5 meters, so it's a huge comparing to the ISO 14 443.
As the vicinity cards have to operate at a greater distance, the necessary magnetic field is less than
5 ampere/m.
It's from zero 15 to 5 ampere/m.
So finally, the Felica standard, which is a contactless RFID smart card system for Sony in Japan,
primarily used in electronic magnetic money cards.
It operates also at 1350 six megahertz, and the proximity of ten centimeter or less is required for
communication.
So what are the other standards in general?
In fact, the standards that define the different type of application in the contactless fields are
many.
And here are some of them.
So we have ISO standards as we said for identity cards.
Then we have the EMV standard for payment cards for banking cards.
Third one we have NFC forum for mobile phones.
Then we have ICAO for passports.
And for example we have also ciphers for transportation cards.
And here we are in the summary of this part.
So NFC is a wireless communication technology that allows devices to communicate with each other over
short distances, typically less than four centimeters.
A Pic is a smart card that uses inductive coupling to communicate with its coupler, or let's call it
also PCD.
The magnetic field created is characterized by a 1350 six megahertz carrier frequency, which is the
high frequency radio band.
Finally, three standards details the NFC communication between a card and the reader, which are ISO
14,443, ISO 15,693, and Felica.